CHIEMERIE OKORO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | DATA SCIENTIST

Software engineer and Data Scientist with 7 years+ professional experience in Software development, statistical machine learning, Object-oriented, and functional Programming. I am efficient at Python, R, JavaScript, Go development processes in desktop app development, web development, data analytics, data science, and mobile app development.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

May 2023—Till present | **Cyberbyte Software Limited**, Nigeria **Software Engineer**

- Developed Payment APIs for the agency banking solution ApeironPay for NairaPoint and HorizonPay
- Developed a rule-based fraud analysing system for the agency banking Solution (ApeironPay) with FastApi, and React

March 2021–May 2023 | **ELNEXU CONSULT**, Lagos, Nigeria

Data Scientist

- Analysed the data collected to identify patterns and trends that can help agency bankers make data driven decisions.
- Monitors the performance of agency banking products and services, identifying areas of improvements and making recommendations to agency bankers.
- Helped in identifying potential risks associated with the agency banking transactions, including fraud, money laundering, and credit risk, and provides recommendations to mitigate these risks.
- Prepares report on company's performance, including customer acquisition and retention rates, and Profitability.
- Used ML to predict customer future purchase behaviour for informed decision.

February 2020-March 2021

Data Scientist | Software Engineer

- Data mining and data analytics with python pandas, NumPy, and matplotlib, and scikit learn.
- Used the binary classification to predict discrete classes on a target population.
- Built analytical dashboards for data visualization for the upper echelon.
- Played a key role in system optimization projects
- Trained a machine learning model to detect and predict voters' apathy.

+2348137866603

chiemeriedroid@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/chiemerieokoro-96a471171/

github.com/Chiemerie1

EDUCATION

2009-2014
Ebonyi State University,
Abakaliki, Nigeria
Bachelors of Science,
Applied Statistics.

SKILLS

Python, Django, Tkinter, Kivy, FastAPI

Pandas, Matplotlib, TensorFlow

MySQL, Postgres MongoDB

HTML, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript

Flutter, Solidity, R, Golang, MS Excel, MS Power BI, GitHub

- Developed a thrift webapp using Django, and Tailwind CSS for a financial organisation
- Trained a machine learning model for predicting the manufacturing accuracy of a synthetic commodity using backpropagation
- Built a blockchain wallet using solidity, web3 and python for an organisation

February 2020–June 2020 | **First Bank of Nigeria**, Abakaliki, Nigeria **Data Analyst**

- Analysed weekly market data for the BDM by cleaning with Excel Power Query visualised by creating an interactive dashboard with Pivot Tables.
- Cleaned, analysed and produce an interactive dashboard using power
 BI
- Trained a machine learning regression model to learn and predict the future savings prospect of customers.
- Provided end analytics solutions across supply chains to improve visibility and performance
- Collect and analyse large sets of data to uncover patterns and insights.
- Created and maintained data dashboards and reports to communicate findings to stakeholders.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to identify and prioritize business problems that can be solved with data analysis.
- Develop and implemented MS Business intelligence tools and techniques to affirm business decisions.
- Utilize statistical and data visualization such as Power BI to present findings in a clear and concise manner.
- Communicated the results and findings effectively to both technical and non-technical stakeholders through Power BI reports

September 2015–April 2018 | Cambridge Analytica, London, UK Data Scientist and Developer

- Trained a machine learning model that predicts house prices based on house location using linear regression, lasso and decision tree regressor, used gridSearchCV parameter optimisation, determine the best model and deployed to the cloud using python Flask for the server, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML and CSS for the frontend.
- Data mining and data analytics with python pandas, NumPy, matplotlib, and scikit learn.
- Used the binary classification to predict discrete classes on a target population.
- Built analytical dashboards for data visualization for the upper echelon using MS Excel.
- Trained a machine learning model to detect and predict voters' apathy.

- Based on my tasks as a Data scientist and Statistician, my opinion was instrumental in driving decision making concerning company undertaking.
- Generating quantitative decision support to optimize data and data modelling
- Supporting projects through completion.

July 2013–September 2015 | Anson Links, USA.

Software Engineer | Django developer

- Built a pool system thrifting webapp for a community of workers that keeps track of their deposits, merge and link depositors to receivers using Django web framework.
- Built an internal micro-banking system for a financial institution using Django web framework.
- Worked with management to gather data and information that aided in decision making.
- Programmed a dashboard with Pandas, matplotlib and Streamlit to enable instant decision making.
- Built a carwash point of sale desktop application using Python built-in GUI (Tkinter); used MongoDB for its database.
- Migrated the carwash database technology from MongoDB to MySQL and connected it with MySQL client on client's request.
- Built a pharmacy e-commerce app with JAVA; with a delivery solution functionality that enable despatch riders register and be sort after based on proximity radius.
- Built an inventory and customer relational database with Python GUI (Tkinter) and MongoDB.
- Built an open-source banking system with Django, and Tailwind CSS, and JavaScript for the frontend
- Built and Open-source Android Cryptocurrency application with flutter.

2012–2013 | Local Government Service Commission, Abakaliki, Nigeria Planning, Research & Statistics, and IT development

- Researched the specifications of a customer relational management software by working with the register department, and liaising with the HRMs of the 13 LGAs.
- Determined the best approach through which the computer CRM application was developed.
- Built a MYSQL database for the register department for easy storage of files and visitors' data
- Built a simple interface with required file fields and connected it to the database for ease of access in writing, reading, updating, and deleting data from the database.
- Developed an e-dispatch mechanism for office mail delivery within the organisation.
- Developed a crop and crop sales database for the Agric department. With Django [Python]

- Redeveloped the register department software with Django
- Assisted in the planning and budgeting